（上条(かみじょう)）
完全記憶能力
Perfect memorization.
インデックスは
脳の85パーセントを使って―
Index apparently used 85% of her brain's capacity to memorize 103,000 grimoires.
10万3,000冊を記憶しているらしい
残り15パーセントしか
脳を使えない彼女は―
Since she can only use the remaining 15%, she needs to have her memories erased every year or else she'll die...
１年ごとに記憶を消去しなければ
死んでしまうと魔術師は言う
...said the magician.
その日まで あと３日
And only three days remain until that limit.
…て 俺 ３日もダウンしてたのか？
～♪
Wait, I was out cold for three days?!
Well then, Kamijyo-chan, Sensei's going out now.
（小萌(こもえ)）
じゃ 上条ちゃん
先生 お出かけします
#05 Limit
Midnight
I might be back late,
so take care of the house while I'm away.
帰りは
遅くなるかもですけど
お留守番
お願いなのです
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
お願いだから―
Please, don't hurt Touma anymore!!!
もう当麻(とうま)を傷つけないで！
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
リミットまで 残り12時間と38分
There's twelve hours and thirty-eight minutes left until the limit.
We were going to see the effect of the "fetter"
depending on whether you chose to escape or not,
逃げ出さないかどうか 足かせの
効果を見てみたかったんだけど
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）予想以上だったね
（上条）足かせ？
but this exceeds our expectations.
Fetter...
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
そのおもちゃを
取り上げられたくなかったら―
If you don't want us to take away that "toy",
then I suggest you throw away the idea of escaping.
もう逃亡の可能性は
捨てたほうがいい　分かるね？
You hear me?
You'll be all right.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）大丈夫だよ
（上条）うん？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
私が取り引きすれば…
If I negotiate with them,
your daily life won't get altered any further.
当麻の日常は これ以上 壊させない
I won't let them step any further into your life...
これ以上は
絶対に踏み込ませないから
...so it's... all-
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）平気…
（上条）あっ…
（小萌）あっ…
（上条）インデックス
Index!
（神裂(かんざき)）
私です
It's me.
（神裂）
…と言って 伝わりますか？
You know who I am?
Kanzaki... was it?
（上条）
神裂 …だっけ？
We don't need to know each other's names.
（神裂）
お互い
名前を知る必要はないでしょう
Is she... is Index there?
あの子は…
インデックスはいますか？
Must I wake her?
起こさなきゃダメか？
Good.
（神裂）
ちょうどいい
そのまま話を聞いてください
Listen as you are.
The limit is tonight at midnight.
リミットは 今夜 午前０時です
（神裂）
私たちは その時刻に合わせて
全てを終わらせるよう―
We are preparing our schedule to finish everything to match that exact time.
スケジュールを組み上げています
Why are you telling me this?
（上条）
そんなもん…
なんで わざわざ俺に教える？
Now that you've told me,
don't you think I'd resist until the very end?
そんなこと言われちまったら―
死んでも
抵抗したくなっちまうだろう！
（神裂）
別れの時間は必要ありませんか？
Don't you need some time for farewells?
This is neither a conversation nor a negotiation.
（神裂）
これは対話でも交渉でもなく
命令です
It's an order.
Bid her farewell before we arrive and leave that room.
我々が到着する前に
あの子に別れを告げて―
その場を離れなさい
All of you are pushing your own incompetence on others...
どいつも こいつも てめえの無能を
インデックスに押しつけやがって…
You guys are magicians, aren't you?
てめえらは魔術師なんだろう？
Will magic really not solve anything?
ホントに
魔術じゃ何にもできねえのか？
インデックスの
10万3,000冊を使えば―
Won't Index be able to find a solution using her 103,000 grimoires?
どうとでもなるんじゃねえのかよ？
（神裂）
教会は―
Of everything, the Church fears
a rebellion from Index the most.
インデックスの反乱を
最も恐れています
What's that supposed to mean?
どういうことだ？
There are most likely biases amongst those grimoires,
（神裂）
恐らく 10万3,000冊には
偏りがあるのでしょう
such as, she is not allowed to learn anything related to Mind Hound.
あの子の記憶操作に関する魔道書は
覚えさせないといった
じゃ お前らの魔術で
なんとかならねえのか？
Then, your own magic can't solve anything?
There is a fear magicians outside of Necessarius would dispel environments created by magic.
（神裂）
魔術によって作られた環境では―
必要悪の教会(ネセサリウス)以外の魔術師に
解除(ディスペル)されるおそれがある
There is no way the Church would allow such possibilities to happen.
教会が そのような可能性を
残すはずはありません
And most importantly, the act of memorizing grimoires itself signifies the contamination of the brain.
（神裂）
そして 何より―
魔道書を記憶する行為は
脳の汚染を意味しています
えっ？　お前ら
それを知ってて インデックスに…
You guys knowingly let Index...
あとで聞かされた話です
We were only informed afterwards.
Magic... won't solve anything...
何もできませんよ
（神裂）
魔術では
What about... us?
なら 俺たちなら…
（神裂）“俺たち”？
（上条）科学側だよ
Us?
The science side.
We have many methods of scientifically removing people's memories.
人の記憶を科学的に奪う方法なんて
いくらでもある
We could have a solution you don't have that could remove the 103,000 grimoires from her brain.
てめえらにできない方法で
10万3,000冊をえぐり取る方法が
And this is Academy City!
それに ここは学園都市だぜ
There are plenty of espers that can control one's heart.
心を操る能力者なんてのも
たくさんいる
It's too early to give up all hope!
望みを捨てるには
まだまだ早いんだよ
それでも てめえは 努力することも
挑戦することも諦めて―
Are you still going to give up trying or challenging things
and put someone's life at risk?
とりあえず 人の命を
天秤(てんびん)にかけちまおうってのか？
These are cheap words for persuading your enemy.
（神裂）
敵を説得する言葉にしては
安すぎますね
If you look at it from our side,
at least we have successfully saved her life.
逆に言えば 私たちには―
とりあえず あの子の命を
助けてきた実績があります
何の実績も持たないあなたの賭けは
信用できません
We do not trust your bet that has nothing to support itself.
それは 努力でも挑戦でもない
Don't you think that this is neither trying nor challenging,
（神裂）
“無謀”という ひと言に
変換できませんか？
but rather, just, recklessness?
Right.
だよな
In the end, there is no place for a truce.
結局 分かり合うことなんざ
できねえんだな
上等だ
Fine.
Then I'll crush you, arch-rival.
それじゃ つぶすぜ 宿敵
I'll save her and steal all the heroic moments for myself!
あいつを助けて てめえの見せ場を
全部 横取りしてやるからな
If she collapses again, consider it too late.
（神裂）
もし次に
あの子が倒れるようなことがあれば
危険だと思ってください
See you at midnight, then.
それでは 今晩０時に
There really is little time remaining...
残り時間は 本当に僅かですが…
最後にステキな悪あがきを
Show us a sensational struggle to the end...
“記憶喪失”
Memory loss.
Loss of memory due to aging is one kind of memory loss,
“老化や酔って記憶がなくなるのも
記憶喪失の一種で―”
as well as the loss of memory caused by the stoppage of blood to the brain.
“脳の血液が止まって
記憶が飛んだりするのも”…
ふ～ん…
Loss of memory from side effects of halothane, isoflurane, general anesthesia, or benzodiazepine, same thing...
“ハロセン イソフルランなどの
全身麻酔や―”
“ベンゾジアゼピン類などの
薬の副作用で記憶を失うことも”
I'm not getting anywhere like this.
つうか
このままじゃラチが明かねえ
あっ 携帯の料金明細？
Cellphone bill?
あっ そうだ！
Right!
I'll just ask Komoe-sensei to introduce me to
a neurological research or mental ability institute!
小萌先生に―
脳医学だか精神能力関係の
研究者を紹介してもらえば…
（上条）
何やってんだよ？　小萌先生
What the hell are you doing, Komoe-sensei?!
Looks like I'll just have to call random places...
こうなりゃ 手当たりしだいに
当たるしかなさそうだな
ンッ… 次！
Next.
ンッ… くそ！
Damn it!
Hello?
Perfect memorization?
（研究員）
完全記憶能力？
Yes, I know of it...
（研究員）
はい 知ってますが
ですから
症状を教えていただかなければ
But, you need to tell me the symptoms...
Huh?! Magic?
はぁ？　魔術？
今 何時だと思ってるんですか？
もうすぐ12時なんですよ
What time of the day do you think it is right now?
It's almost midnight, you know?
Hello?
Hello?!
もしもし？　まったく…
Gosh!
インデックス？
Index...
Outta the way.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
ジャマだ
Refer to Moonchild.
クロウリーの書を参照
We'll have an angel descend and create its temple in this room.
天使を降臨させ
この部屋に神殿を築く
We're going to kill her memories.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
この子の記憶を殺し尽くすぞ
あっ… ま… 待てよ　待ってくれ
W-Wait...
Please wait.
There's 1,800,000 espers in this Academy City...
この学園都市には
180万もの能力者がいる
...and more than one thousand research facilities!
研究機関だって1,000以上ある
（上条）
そういう所を頼っていけば―
If we go to those places, we might not have to use this last resort!
こんな最悪な方法に頼らなくて
済むかもしれねえんだ
（上条）
お前たちだって こんな方法
取りたかねえんだろう？
You guys don't want to use this method either, right?
You're hoping that there's some other way deep inside your heart, right?
心の底じゃ―
“ほかの方法はありませんか”って
お祈りしてんだろう？
Then wait a bit longer!
だったら もう少し待ってくれ
俺が必ず 誰もが笑って―
I'll find a way to resolve this so that everyone is smiling and happy in the end!
誰もが幸福な結末を
探し出してみせるから
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
言いたいことは それだけか？
Is that all you have to say?
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
ンッ… 見ろ！
Look at her!
Can you spit out the same words in front of her?
君は この子の前で
同じセリフが言えるのか？
A person who has fought against this all her life...
ずっと耐え続けてきた人間に
A patient who can't even open her eyes because of all the pain...
激痛で
目を開けることもできない病人に
“試したいことがあるから
待ってろ”なんて言えるのか？
Can you tell her to wait a bit because you want to try some stuff out?
To let doctors whose name and face are unknown... to let them play around with her body...
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
顔も名前も分からない医者どもに
この子の体を好き勝手にいじらせ
薬漬けにすることを
よしとするだなんて
...and let her waste away with drugs...
...that's not something a human can come up with...
そんなものは人間の考えじゃない
Answer me!
答えろ！　君は まだ人間か？
Are you still human?
それとも
人間を捨てたバケモノなのか？
Or a monster that quit being human?
This is an artifact necessary for removing her memory,
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
これは あの子の記憶をなくすのに
必要な道具　魔術の霊装だ
a magic ornament.
Touch it with your right hand,
and that should be enough to dispel its magic.
君の右手が触れれば
それだけで力を失うはずだ
We're just killing her memories.
僕らが殺すのは記憶だけだ
命は助かる
She'll still have her life.
But if your trials fail, she will die.
だが 君の試みが失敗したら
あの子は死んでしまう
それでも できるか？
あの子の前で
So can you still do it?
In front of her?
Can you still take this away in front of a girl in that much pain?
これだけ苦しんでいる女の子の前で
取り上げることができるのか？
If you trust your abilities that much, then do it!
そんなに自分の力を信じているなら
やってみろ
You blasted mutant that thinks of yourself as a hero!
ヒーロー気取りのミュータントが！
My name is Index.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
私の名前は
インデックスっていうんだよ
I'd be grateful if you could help me fill up my stomach.
おなかいっぱい ご飯を
食べさせてくれると うれしいな
The ritual will begin at 12:15 AM.
儀式の開始は 午前０時15分
しし座の力を借りて 記憶を殺す
We will borrow the powers of Leo to kill her memories.
（神裂）
はい
Understood.
（上条）
なあ　魔術師
Hey, magician.
How should I say my final goodbye to her?
俺は最後に この子に何と言って
お別れをすればいいと思う？
I don't have a single second to spare for that.
そんな くだらないことに
割く時間など どこにもない
Would you mind just disappearing from here, monster?
ここから消えてくれないか？
バケモノ
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
君の右手は 僕の炎を打ち消した
Your right hand took out my flames.
それが どういう原理だか
いまだに理解できないけど
I still don't understand the principle behind it,
どんなに些細(ささい)なことでも―
but I don't want any single thing to influence the ritual.
これから行う儀式に
影響を及ぼされたくはない
Why...
なんで…
Why don't I even have the ability to save one girl in pain?
なんで俺には―
たったひとり 苦しんでる女の子を
助けることもできねえのかな
儀式の開始まで
まだ10分ほど時間がありますね
There's about ten minutes before the start of the ritual, correct?
私たちが
初めて記憶を消すと誓った夜は―
The night when we swore to erase her memories for the first time,
we wept next to her the entire night.
ひと晩中
あの子のそばで泣きじゃくりました
だ… だが 今のこいつは
何をするか分からないんだ
B-But!
We don't know what this guy's gonna do in his current state!
What if this guy tries to commit a double suicide the second we let our eyes off him?
僕たちが目を離した隙に
心中でも図ったら どうする？
Don't you think he would've touched the cross already?
（神裂）
それなら さっさと十字架に
触れているとは思いませんか？
（神裂）
彼が まだ人間だと
確信していたからこそ―
It is exactly because we have
confirmed him to still be human
あなたも試してみたのでしょう？
that you wanted to test him, right?
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
しかし…
But...
どのみち
時が満ちるまで儀式は行えません
Either way, the ritual won't begin until the time comes.
彼の未練を残しておけば―
If he still has regrets,
then there is a danger that we will have obstacles during the ritual, Stiyl.
儀式の途中で妨害が入る危険が
残りますよ ステイル
You have ten minutes!
10分だ　いいな？
Okay?
当麻…
Tou...ma...
インデックス…
Index.
Sorry.
ごめん
Touma, there seems to be a formation in this room.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻　部屋に 何か陣が張ってある
Something about a regeneration magic.
（上条）
回復魔術だってさ
Magic... whose?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
魔術って 誰が？
あっ また魔術師が来たんでしょう
当麻 逃げなきゃダメだよ！
Those magicians came again, right?
Touma, you need to run!
It's okay now, Index.
もういいんだ インデックス
Touma!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻…
終わったんだよ もう
It's over.
It's all over.
（上条）終わっちまったんだ
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻…
Touma...
Sorry.
（上条）
ごめん　俺 強くなるから
I'll become stronger.
もう二度と負けねえから
I won't ever lose again.
お前をこんなふうに扱う連中
Those people that treat you this way,
I'll kick every one of their butts, that's how strong I'll become...
全部 残らず １人残らず
ぶっ飛ばせるくらい強くなるから
Wait for me.
待ってろよ
This time...
今度は… 今度は
絶対 完璧(かんぺき)に助け出してみせるから
This time, I'll save you all the way.
Okay...
分かった　待ってる
I'll wait...
ちくしょう…
こんな最悪な終わり方ってないよな
Damn this!
I can't allow this worst kind of ending, right?
結局 何もできなかった
I couldn't do anything in the end.
インデックスの脳の
85パーセントを占める―
I couldn't do anything about the 103,000 grimoires that occupy 85% of her brain,
10万3,000冊をどうにかすることも
nor could I protect the one-year's worth of memories inside the remaining 15%.
残る15パーセントに
詰め込まれた―
たった１年分の思い出を
守り抜くことだって
Wait, huh?
あ… あれ？
（神裂）
彼女の脳の85パーセントは―
85% of her brain is allocated to the 103,000 grimoires.
10万3,000冊の記憶のために
使われています
そのため 彼女は 常人の
15パーセントしか脳を使えません
That is why she can only use 15% of a normal person's brain capacity.
Memory erasure takes place in exact one year periods.
記憶の消去は
きっかり１年周期に行います
（上条）
ちょっと待て
Hold it...
15パーセントも使って―
Why can she only live for one year with 15% of her brain?
たった１年分しか記憶できないって
どういうことだ？
いや それ以前に―
No, even before that...
...how did Kanzaki get to numbers like 85% or 15%?
神裂は 一体 どうやって
85パーセントだの―
15パーセントだのって数字を
導き出したんだ？
Hello?
（小萌）
はい？
Ah, that must be your voice, Kamijyo-chan!
あっ その声は上条ちゃんですね？
先生ん家(ち)の電話を
勝手に使っちゃダメですよ
You shouldn't be using Sensei's phone without her permission, you know?
えっ？　完全記憶能力？
Huh, perfect memorization?
Yes, it is a rare case, but that by itself is just a physical condition.
えっ？
ええ 確かに珍しい例ですけど
それ自体は ただの体質ですよ
それって １年間の記憶だけで―
And will one use up 15% of a brain's capacity in one year?
脳を15パーセントも
使っちまうんですか？
Rather, it's a miserable physical condition where one's brain breaks down around the age of six to seven, right?
…てことは ６歳か７歳で
脳がパンクしちまうほど―
絶望的な体質ってことに
なりますよね？
It's true that people with perfect memorization can't forget the single smallest thing,
確かに 完全記憶能力は―
どんな小さなゴミ記憶でも
忘れることはできませんけど
それで脳がパンクすることは
絶対にありえません
but one's brain definitely won't break down because of that.
A human's brain can store 140 years worth of memories to begin with.
人間の脳は もともと
140年分の記憶が可能ですから
It's impossible for a human brain to break down?
記憶がパンクすることなんて
ありえない？
プハ～ッ…
We just don't have one place for memories to begin with.
そもそも 人の記憶とは
ひとつだけではありません
We have semantic memory,
which governs language and knowledge.
（小萌）
言葉や知識をつかさどる
意味記憶
運動の慣れなんかを
つかさどる手続き記憶
We have procedural memory,
which governs the know-how of your motor functions.
そして
思い出をつかさどる―
And finally, we have episodal memory,
which governs your memories.
エピソード記憶って
具合にですね
Something like that.
So, there's plenty of them.
いろいろあるのですよ いろいろ
Plenty.
So, umm... Sensei.
えっと… 先生　言ってる意味が
分からないんですけど
I don't get what you're saying.
Basically, no matter how much knowledge you force into the brain,
つまりですね
いくら知識を詰め込んでも―
それで
記憶が圧迫されるなんてことは―
it won't create so much pressure that the brain blows open.
脳医学上 絶対にありえませ～ん
That's impossible, at least, in neurology~
インデックスの完全記憶能力は―
Index's perfect memorization isn't a life-threatening condition.
人の命を
脅かすようなものじゃなかった
だとすれば 教会は
神裂にウソをついてたことになる
That would mean that the Church lied to Kanzaki.
Then, why is Index in pain?
じゃ なんで
インデックスは苦しんでんだ？
教会が
インデックスの頭をいじって―
The Church messed with Index's brain...
...and made it so that she would die
if her memories weren't killed in one-year periods.
１年周期で記憶を消さなければ
死んでしまうという細工をしたんだ
10万3,000冊を持つインデックスが
絶対に裏切ることのないように
That way, Index, who possesses 103,000 grimoires, would never betray them.
That way, Index's friends will have to swallow their tears and obey them.
（上条）
インデックスの仲間たちが―
涙をのんで
従わなければならないように
But what exactly did the Church do to her?
けど 教会の細工ってのは一体…
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
そんなに自分の力を信じているなら
やってみろ
If you trust your abilities that much, then do it!
You blasted mutant that pretends to be a hero!
ヒーロー気取りのミュータントが！
I'm not pretending to be a hero.
（上条）
ヒーロー気取りじゃねえ
I will become one!
ヒーローになるんだ！
…て あれ？
Huh?
Nothing's happening, which means...
何も変化なしって…
異能の力に触れてない？
...I'm not touching anything supernatural?
So, is there any place I haven't touched yet?
…てことは
まだ触れてない部分がある？
まさか…
Don't tell me...
（スパーク音）
ウワッ！
Warning.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
警告　第３章 第２節
Chapter 3, Verse 2.
Confirmed the penetration of seals 1 to 3.
第１から第３までの
全結界の貫通を確認
Preparing to regenerate.
再生準備 失敗　自動再生は不可能
Failure.
Auto-regeneration cannot be carried out.
Presently, in order to protect the library of 103,000 grimoires,
現状 10万3,000冊の
書庫の保護のため―
侵入者の迎撃を優先します
prioritizing engaging with the intruder.
Reverse engineering the magic formula that destroyed the barriers, based on the 103,000 grimoires.
書庫内の10万3,000冊により
結界を貫通した魔術の術式を逆算
Failure.
失敗　該当する魔術は発見できず
No applicable spell found.
術式の構成を暴き 対侵入者用の
ローカルウエポンを組み上げます
Forcing the disclosure of the spell's composition and constructing a local weapon against the intruder.
Successfully constructed the most effective weapon against the intruder.
侵入者個人に対して 最も有効な
魔術の組み合わせに成功しました
これより 特定魔術
“聖(セント)ジョージの聖域”を発動
Now initiating local weapon, "St. George's Sanctuary".
Proceeding to destroy intruder.
侵入者を破壊します
～♪
Next Episode
St. George's Sanctuary...
...has created an infinite amount of distance between me and Index.
（上条）
“聖ジョージの聖域”は―
But just one more step...
...if I can just take one more step...
俺とインデックスの間に
果てしない距離を作る
I will definitely reach her!
Next time, "Imagine Breaker".
でも もう１歩…
あと１歩 踏み出せば 必ず届くから
When science and magic cross paths,
this epic will begin!
次回 “幻想殺し(イマジンブレイカー)”
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる